他们终于要来抓走这些巫师了
They have come for the witches at last!
在我们来这里之前
Before we came here,
我们本来有机会把巫师交出去
we had a chance to give the witches up,
但他们用巫术迷惑了你们
but they enchanted you all.
现在是你们悔过的机会
Now is your moment to repent.
把他们从我们身边赶走
Let us rid ourselves of them!
我们如今面临的危险  都要怪他们
They are the ones to blame for the danger we are facing today,
他们必须为此受到惩罚
and they must answer for it!
众所周知
Everyone knows
一直以来你们才是我们真正的敌人
that you have been our true enemy this whole time!
拦住他们  别让他们跑了
Hold them! Don't let them go!
不要让他们离开
Do not let them leave!
我们要用他们作为筹码来换取活命的机会
We will use them as a bargain for our lives.
我制住他了  我制住他了
I have him! I have him!
退后
Stand back!
巫师用刀抵着我的喉咙
The witch has me by the throat!
我们必须马上离开
We have to leave now.
带他们去河边  去河边
Get them to the river. To the river.
-让恶魔们走  -阿尔卡
- Let the devils pass! - Arca!
我们很快就能除掉他们
We'll be rid of them soon enough!
玛特尔
Matal!
快走
Go.
跟他们一起走  活下去
Go with them. Live.
我爱你
I love you.
玛特尔
Matal.
她干什么
What is she doing?
博
Bow?
我要跟你们一起走
I'm coming with you.
跟我走  快跟上
Come with me! Follow!
可风
Kofun.
我对你没有用处
You have no use for me.
放我走吧
Let me go.
他应该死
He deserves to die.
不
No.
如果我真的是恶魔  我会很乐意杀了你
If I were a devil for real, I would take great pleasure.
但我们不是那种部落
But we're not that kind of tribe.
我是塔玛奇俊
I am Tamacti Jun.
凯恩女王麾下的猎巫将军
Witchfinder General for Queen Kane
也是帕岩的神圣守护者
and the Holy Guardians of the Payan.
猎巫者大人  您终于来救我们了
At last, Witchfinder, you have come to save us.
跪下
On your knees.
什么
What?
所有人都跪下
All of you.
要想活命
For your lives...
把杰拉马瑞尔的孩子交出来
give up the children of Jerlamarel.
我们艾肯尼人是良善之人
We Alkenny are good people.
安分守己
Quiet people.
求您了
Please...
猎巫者大人  求您了
Witchfinder, please.
巫师们都已经走了
The witches are gone.
在被证明不是前
Until proven otherwise...
你们都是巫师
you're all witches.
神圣守护者
Holy Guardian!
我是盖瑟拜克斯
This is Gether Bax!
那些巫师都逃走了
The witches, they've run!
请跟我来
Follow me!
等等  这是条死路
Wait. It's a dead end.
不  孩子  我们从这里下去
No, my boy. This is where we descend.
快看
Look.
爸
Dad.
这是你做的吗  就你一个人
You did this? Alone?
杰拉马瑞尔能做到的  我也可以  只是做得更大
Anything Jerlamarel can do, I can do, only bigger.
是什么东西  我们下面有什么
What is it? What's below us?
是自由  妈妈
Freedom, Mama.
爸爸造了条船
Dad built a boat.
儿子
Son.
你是什么时候造的这个船
When did you do this?
一有时间就来弄
When I could.
你会很惊讶在你每天早上睁眼前
You'd be surprised how much you can accomplish
就能完成多少事
before your eyes even get open in the morning.
为什么
Why?
跟你们一样  我也希望这一天永远不会到来
Like you, I hoped this day would never come.
但你已经提前做好了准备
But you prepared for it?
是的  没错
Yes, I did.
因为这个准备  我们将能活着见到明天的太阳
And because of it, we will live to see tomorrow.
逃走的那些人里...
The ones that fled...
其中有一个是建造师吗
was one of them a builder?
是的  而且技术非常高超
Yes. Yes, a very skilled one.
过河
Cross.
-爸  -我知道  我能听见
- Dad. - Shh. I know. I can hear them.
把我的剑给我
Give me my sword.
他们就在前方  两岸都有
They are ahead. Both sides.
我们无声地穿过去
We travel silently.
我一直在寻找你...
I have been looking for you...
找了一辈子了
for a lifetime.
你出生的时候  我也在
I was there when you were born.
我听到过你最初的啼哭
I heard your first cries.
从那以后
And ever since,
我倾尽一生  试图再次寻找到你
I have devoted my life to finding you again.
我杀了那么多人  才终于找到你
I have laid waste to so many lives to reach you.
现在...
And now...
接下来要怎样
what next?
附近  有一个全是你们同族的村子
Nearby, there's a village filled with your kinsmen
都跪在地上  乞求我的宽恕
all on their knees begging for my forgiveness.
或许你可以换回他们一条命
Perhaps you can purchase it for them.
说话
Speak.
让我听听你的声音
Let me hear the sound of your voices
自你出生时的啼哭之后  我可再没听到过了
for the first time since they were newborn wails.
自报身份吧
Announce yourselves.
让我护送你去见你的女王
And let me escort you to meet your queen.
照做的话
Do it...
村民们就能活下来
and the village lives.
不配合是吗
No?
救命啊
Help!
不要
No!
-巴巴  -玛格拉
- Baba! - Maghra.
等等  妈妈
Wait, Mama.
不要
No!
妈妈
Mom!
快走
Go!
阿尔卡
Arca!
下流有什么
What lies downriver?
我们能继续追吗
Can we pursue?
我被刺穿了
I've been run through.
前方有什么
What lies ahead?
或许能饶你一命
Perhaps you can be saved.
宽阔的水域  都是深水区
Open waters, deep water.
他们会漂得很快
They'll move quickly.
你肯定追不上他们
You will not be able to catch them.
救救我
Help me.
好了  这样应该能给你节省点时间
There. That should save you some time.
回村庄去  把他们全杀光
Return to the village. Kill them all.
信使
Herald.
传消息给凯恩女王
Message for Queen Kane.
就说巫师们逃走了
The witches have escaped.
塔玛奇俊传消息回来了
Tamacti Jun sends news.
他找到那些巫师了吗
Did he locate the witches?
是的  但他们暂时逃走了
Yes. But, for the moment, they escaped him.
他们又从他手中逃脱了吗
They escaped him again?
-怎么逃的  -他没说
- How? - He doesn't say.
那我们只能猜测或臆想了
So we must guess, or invent for ourselves.
安夫人
Lady An,
当神之火焰灼烧我们时
when the God Flame burns our skin,
你会怪罪神还是你自己
do you blame God or yourself?
都不会怪  女王陛下
Neither one, my queen.
我会怪我的女仆没有给我遮挡
I blame my maid for not shading me.
永远不能怪罪神  没人怪罪您
Gods are not blamed. No one is blaming you.
但这个消息或许意味着塔玛奇俊该回来了
But perhaps this news means Tamacti Jun should return home.
不不不
No. No, no, no.
但要承担追捕任务
But to undertake such a journey,
塔玛奇俊需要更多的士兵
Tamacti Jun will need more soldiers.
陛下  求您了...
Majesty, please--
再多派些去  全部派过去
Send more. Send all of them.
他们是父亲和母亲
These are fathers and mothers,
丈夫和妻子
husbands and wives,
女儿和儿子
daughters and sons.
他们的家人承受了他们缺席的苦楚
Their families have suffered their absences.
他们已经厌倦了这种  没有结果的远征
They are tired of this... fruitless crusade.
他们无法理解
It's beyond their understanding.
神圣机器也不堪重负  陛下
The holy machines are groaning too, Your Majesty.
众神自身也无法理解
The gods themselves do not understand this.
难道你还能听懂众神说的话了不成
But you understand what the gods are saying?
是的  他们在说"够了"
Yes! They are saying "Enough!"
够了
Enough!
瞧啊
There...
我们的古代《宪法》里规定了
in our ancient constitution.
"君王将统领议会
"And the monarch shall rule the parliament,
至死方休"
and the monarch shall rule until death."
我没感觉不适
I'm not feeling unwell.
陛下  帕岩人民都这么说
Majesty, here is what the people of Payan say.
你不过是把他们当祈祷垫践踏
As you fuck them like prayer mats.
事情摆在眼前  您花了二三十年时间追捕巫师
Plainly, simply, you have chased the witches for a generation.
却未曾寻到过一个
Yet none has been found.
您牺牲了我们的军队
You have sacrificed our army,
掏空了我们的宝库
emptied our treasure houses.
仍然无法证明有邪恶力量存在
Still there is no proof of evil power.
只有...
Just...
一个您爱过的男人离开了您
a man you once loved who ran away from you.
人民都说我们是一个
They say we are a nation governed
被破碎之心统治的国度
by a broken heart.
这是杰拉马瑞尔留下的信息
A message from Jerlamarel.
等孩子们准备好抛下我们时
A message to present to the children
就转交给他们
once they were ready to leave us behind.
是用眼睛才能看到的信息
It is a message for eyes.
杰拉马瑞尔还留下更多"惊喜"
More surprises from Jerlamarel?
我向他保证过
I gave him my word.
我会等到他们完全准备好  才交给他们
I would present it no sooner than when they were ready for it.
这是他给我的最后一条信息
It's the last of my messages from him.
我对他最后的承诺
Last of my promises to him.
确定吗
Are we sure?
确定
Yes, we are.
念吧
Go ahead.
"我亲爱的孩子们
"My dear children...
河流只是开始
the river is the beginning.
你们回到我身边的漫长旅途的第一步
The first step of your long journey back to me.
沿着河流到薰衣草地
Follow the river to the lavender.
薰衣草大道"
The great lavender road."
薰衣草大道是真实存在的
The lavender road is real.
"然后沿着薰衣草大道走到觉悟大宅
"Then follow the lavender road to the House of Enlightenment.
我将在那里建立新王国
There, I will build a new kingdom.
成为这阴暗世界里的一道耀眼光芒
A bright shining light in a world of darkness.
有一天  你们将来到我身边  知我所知
And one day, you will come to me and know what I know.
并将这知识
And carry this knowledge
传递到地球最黑暗的角落"
forward to the darkest corners of the earth."
-"有眼能视之人必须跟随我"  -"...必须跟随我"
- "Those with eyes to see must follow me." - "...see must follow me."
所以我们就沿着河前进吗  要走多远
So, what? We just follow the river? For how long?
他会留下标记给我们
He'll leave us signs.
-我们能到达目的地  -真的吗
- We'll make it. - Will we?
我们还有别的选择吗
What other choice do we have?
我们有选择
We have a choice.
听我说
Listen to me.
看着我
Look at me.
旅途越长
The longer the journey,
其挑战越巨大
the more profound its challenges,
对行走者的影响也越深远
the more it changes all who endure it.
像这样的旅途
A journey like this one...
我们之中能活下来的人
Those of us who could survive it,
我担心在路途结束后
I fear, would emerge on the other end of it
会变得面目全非
unrecognizable to each other.
如果我们变得连自己都不认识自己了
What kind of answers will the House of Enlightenment provide
觉悟大宅又会给我们何种答案
to any of us if we no longer recognize ourselves?
无论投票结果如何  我都会遵守
I will abide to whatever our vote decides,
但你们得听好了
but you must hear this.
我们可以选择继续过现在的生活
We have a choice to live as we are.
我们可以和猎巫者拉开些距离
We can gain some distance on the Witchfinder,
但此时他一定正继续追捕我们
who most certainly continues his pursuit as we speak.
我们能迁移到远离他势力范围的天涯海角
And we can move far away from anywhere he might track us...
过着简单  宁静的生活
and live our lives simply, and quietly,
永不分离
and together.
妈妈
Mama,
我不知道我能否认识到真实的自己
I don't know that I can ever know who I really am
除非我知道我的出身
until I know where I came from.
而想确定这一点  就必须找到杰拉马瑞尔
And I can't know that until I know Jerlamarel.
你呢
And you?
我不认为自己注定是个躲避世界的人
I don't think I'm meant to be someone who hides from the world.
我不认为我想当一个无视真相的人
I don't think I want to be someone who ignores the truth
就因为我害怕真相也许残忍
because I'm afraid of what it might mean.
我知道了
I see.
我们开始投票吗
Shall we take the vote?
支持离开河流去找庇护所的人请投票
All those in favor of leaving the river and finding shelter.
支持跟随杰拉马瑞尔脚步的人请投票
All those in favor of following the trail of Jerlamarel.
还有一个人未投票
There's still one vote left to be cast.
-不  -我们是一个部族  哈妮瓦
- No. - We are one tribe, Haniwa.
我们才是一个部族
We are one tribe.
我们
We.
从一开始就一起经历了一切的人
The ones who have been in this together from the beginning.
我同意帕丽丝
I agree with Paris.
现在我们是仅存的艾肯尼人
Right now we are all that remain of the Alkenny,
博莱昂也是
and Bow Lion shares that connection.
艾肯尼人为了自保  宁愿把我们
The Alkenny were willing to hand us over to the Witchfinder
交给猎巫者
in order to save themselves.
他们只是做了该做的事
They did what they did.
但他们也教导了你  喂养了你
But they also taught you, they fed you,
爱护你  他们是你的朋友
they loved you, and befriended you.
为了救你们  他们被迫离乡背井
They uprooted their lives to save yours.
但是一有机会  他们就背叛了我们
And the very first chance they got, they betrayed us all.
小船上就我们六个人  大家都有权发言
There are six of us on this boat, and everyone will be heard.
不
No.
她和这件事毫无关系
She has absolutely nothing to do with this.
哈妮瓦
Haniwa.
我提议顺着河走
I vote to follow the river.
我赞同哈妮瓦和可风
I vote with Haniwa and Kofun.
阿尔卡  玛特尔和我母亲
Arca, Matal, my mother...
我们已经牺牲了太多  现在只能继续前进
We've sacrificed too much to stop now.
那我们就决定了
Then we have decided.
将军
General!
报告
Report.
有好消息  将军
Good news, General.
我们认为前方地形危险  但也许可以通过
We believe the terrain ahead is treacherous but may be passable.
在我们侦察的时候
The column needn't be camped
纵队不必驻扎超过半天
for more than a half day while we scout it out.
除非我们都死了或是找到杰拉马瑞尔的孩子
No one's stopping until either we're all dead
否则谁也不准停下  明白吗
or we find the children of Jerlamarel. Understood?
-明白  -很好
- Understood. - Good.
那就继续走
So move!
那就必须杀了女王
Then it must be done to kill the queen.
神吗
A god?
这里还有谁相信这个
Who here still believes that?
我们相信什么并不重要
What we believe is not important.
但下层城墙的许多人还相信这一点
Many of the people of the lower walls still believe it.
-如果我们罢黜  -罢黜他们的神
- If we deposed-- - Deposed their god,
他们会崛起叛变
they would rise up.
-我们有士兵  -如此之少
- We have soldiers. - So few.
那我们就不能亲手罢黜她
Then we must not be the ones to depose her.
如果连我们都害怕去做  还有谁会去做
If even we fear to do it, who else possibly would?
要杀神  就必须向神寻求帮助
To kill a god, one must enlist a god.
她的死不能有挣扎的痕迹
Her death must involve no struggle,
不能流血  不能用武器
no blood, no weapon.
不能有人为证据
No evidence of human hand whatsoever.
这样下层城墙的人
And then the people from the lower wall
将会听到他们的女王
will hear that their queen
是因为神出手干预而身亡
was struck down by divine intervention.
他们会说  "此乃正义之举"
And they will say, "This is justice."
我太仁慈了
I'm too merciful.
我们可以祈祷
We could pray.
我祈祷只为得到真相
I pray only for the truth.
你听到了什么
What do you hear?
有一些关于你的新传闻
There are new whispers about you.
是谁在传  安夫人  还是杜恩大人
Who whispers? Lady An? Lord Dune?
除了他们  还有其他人
Yes, and others.
把名字告诉我
Give me names.
他们全部人  女王陛下
All of them, my queen.
-你为什么这么做  -做什么
- Why did you do that? - Do what?
你没有理由去我们要去的地方
You have no reason to go where we're going.
如果你反对我们  你就不必去
If you voted against us, you wouldn't have to.
他们都死了
They're gone.
所有人都死了
Everyone's gone.
我还能去哪里
Where else am I gonna go?
但你还是选择了更艰难的一条路
Still. Still you chose the harder path.
更危险的一条路  但是为什么呢
The more dangerous one. But why?
我不了解你和你妹妹
I don't know you and your sister very well.
我更了解村子里的其他人
Not like I knew the others in the village.
因为只有我们  你无法监视
Because we were the only ones you couldn't spy on.
我知道你是暗影
I know you're a shadow.
我也许不知道你所有的秘密
I may not know all your secrets...
但是大家一直都知道你妹妹的怒火
but your sister's anger has never been a secret to anyone.
我同意走这条路  是因为...
I voted that way because...
我不知道这有什么区别
I don't know what difference it makes,
今天我不想再争执了
and I'm done fighting for today.
她没有生气
She-She isn't angry.
她没有生你的气
I mean, she isn't angry with you.
这些对她来说难以接受  她尽力了
Look, this is just a lot for her, and she's trying her best.
有时这表现为愤怒
And sometimes that comes out as anger.
对你来说也难以接受吧
Isn't it hard for you too?
谢谢你和我说话
Thank you for trying to speak to me.
我现在想一个人静静
I'd like to be alone now.
需要帮忙吗
Hey, do you need help?
需要  我做了这些
Yes. I made these.
-是给博的  -好
- To give to Bow. - Okay.
这个给你和哈妮瓦
For you and Haniwa.
我们今晚要停下过夜
We need to stop for the night.
她需要在篝火边休息
She needs to rest by a fire.
好
Yes.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
她从来没这样跟我说过话
She's never spoken to me that way before.
和我争执  没错
Argued with me, yes.
多次违抗我  但
Defied me many times, but...
但这次太不同寻常
this was just something so different.
如果投票结果是平局  而我打破了平局
If the vote had been a tie and I'd broken that tie against her,
我真不知道她会做什么
I honestly don't know what she would have done.
我们告诉他们要终身隐藏自己身份
We told them to hide who they were their whole lives.
告诉他们任何人知道都不安全
Told them it wasn't safe for anyone to know.
我们从来都不知道他们应该成为谁
We never really knew who they were supposed to be.
他们又怎么能知道
How could they?
也许我们越往河深处走
Maybe the further up this river we go...
他们越容易发现自我
the freer they'll be to find out.
不是吗
Hmm?
女王陛下
Your Majesty?
您的侍女送来了我的请柬
Your handmaiden delivered my invitation?
的确是的  安夫人  她的确送了
Indeed, she did, Lady An. Indeed, she did.
女王陛下  欢迎
Your Majesty, welcome.
性的气息和鸣禽的声音
The smell of sex and the sound of songbirds.
神圣的组合
The divine combination.
正如我在请柬中告诉您
And as I told you in my invitation,
我为您准备了一件特别的欢愉之事
I have a special pleasure in store for you.
没被邀请的人  现在离开
Everyone not invited, leave now.
一首新歌  一只新鸟
A new song. A new bird.
您将成为第一个在宫墙内听到它的人
You will be the first to hear it inside the palace walls.
谁会留下来分享我的喜悦呢
And who will stay to share my delight?
是我  陛下
It is I, Your Majesty.
如果您允许的话
With your permission.
当然  杜恩大人  我知道会是你
Oh, of course, Lord Dune. I know it'd be you.
我们认为那只奇怪的新鸟
We think the strange new bird
被暴风雨吹离了路线
has been blown off course by a storm.
我的渔网工人听到它
My net man heard it singing
在苹果树上唱歌  就设法捉住了它
in the apple trees and managed to trap it.
那他将得到奖赏
Well, then that man will be rewarded.
你也一样  安夫人
As will you, Lady An.
还有你  杜恩大人  谢谢你们想着我
And you, Lord Dune, for thinking of me.
这是我们的新客人
And here is our new guest.
我没听见歌曲
I don't hear a song.
我听说这种鸟
I'm told this particular bird
只有被拿在手里时才会唱歌
only sings when you take it in your hand.
您将是第一个把它拿在手里的人
Yours will be the first hand to hold it.
那么
Well...
打开笼子的门  杜恩大人
then open the door of the cage, Lord Dune.
鸟通常会在人群前战栗
Birds usually tremble among people.
我没听见它战栗抖动的声音
I don't hear it tremble.
也许它不害怕
Perhaps it's not afraid.
而我也不害怕
And I am not afraid.
你看  我的整个议会都同意我死
You see, my whole entire parliament agreeing to my death,
整个堕落的城市都希望我死
this whole rotten city wanting me to die.
我决定不为这座城市而死
I've decided I won't die for this city.
这个城市会为我而死
This city will die for me.
你先死吧
You can go first.
好了
Okay.
我们已经走了很远了
We've traveled a good distance.
只要我们在天亮前继续前进  我们应该没事
As long as we keep moving by daybreak, we should be fine.
我们中有一个人要守夜
One of us should stay awake through the night
保持警惕并且持续生火
to keep watch and tend the fire.
跟我坐一起
Sit with me.
妈妈
Mama...
告诉我  你觉得会是什么样子
Tell me. What do you imagine it will be like?
什么会是什么样子
What will what be like?
他说  "我将在那里建立新王国"
"There, I'll build my kingdom," he says.
我们都要冒着生命危险去这个地方
We're all gonna risk life and limb to get to this place.
那告诉我
So, tell me.
你想象这个王国会是什么样子
What do you imagine this kingdom will be like?
这个嘛
Well...
我想
I imagine...
它会是
it will be...
一个能让我们记住事情的地方
a place where we'll remember things.
关于我们曾经的生活
About what things were like for us once.
关于我们以前的样子
About who we used to be.
关于
About...
如何利用这些知识让生活变得更好
how to use that knowledge to make things better now.
我想
I imagine...
在那里
it will be a place where...
我不再是另类
I won't be the strange one anymore.
我可以帮助建设重要的东西
Where I can help to build something important...
而且我不需要隐藏自己的身份
and do it without having to hide who I am.
如果你父亲为自己建立了一个王国
If your father builds himself a kingdom,
你就是公主了
you would be its princess.
不是那样的
It's not like that.
我愿意做他吩咐的一切  只要我能帮忙
I would do whatever he asked me to do. However I could help.
在这个王国里我是谁
And who would I be in this kingdom?
你是王后
You'd be its queen.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
有视觉的国王
A king with vision...
有视觉的王子和公主
a prince and princess with vision.
而我却看不见
I'd be the one without.
我将会是异类
I'll be the strange one.
人们口中的弱者
The one they say is weak.
我不会让任何人这么说
I would never let anyone say that.
我知道你不会
I know you wouldn't.
我必须要去这个地方  这很重要
It is important for me to reach this place.
但这不是关乎我
But it's not about me.
而是关乎我们大家
It's about all of us.
我们在那能生活地更好  我真的这么觉得
We'll all be better off there. I really believe that.
我们都该休息一会儿
We should all rest a while.
好的
Okay.
可风  我的剑不见了
Kofun, my sword is missing.
我的弓也没了
My bow's gone, too.
-玛格拉  -博  检查船
- Maghra. - Bow, check the boat.
-我以为你们有一人整晚醒着  -来吧
- I thought one of you was awake all night. - Come.
-是的  -来吧
- We were. - Come.
那怎么会这样
Then how did this happen?
有人走过了我们的营地  没有吵醒我们
Someone walked all through our camp, woke none of us,
-也没有被你俩看到  -我不知道
- and was seen by neither of you? - I don't know.
全都没了  是不是
It's all gone now, isn't it?
-帮帮我  我们得走了  -好  走吧
- Help me. We need to go. - Okay. Now walk.
我们不能离开
We can't leave.
我们必须走
We must.
被拿走的都是武器  没有可替代的东西
All that was taken was weapons. It's nothing irreplaceable.
-我有东西不见了  -来吧
- I'm missing something. - Come.
你丢什么了
What are you missing?
一个小袋子  很软  跟拳头一样大
It's a small pouch. It's soft. Size of a fist.
袋子里有什么
What is in the pouch?
对我来说很重要的东西
Something very important to me.
我父亲留给我的唯一东西
The only thing I have left of my father.
-我与他的唯一联系  是...  -好吧
- My only connection to him. It's... - Okay.
这无可替代  我们必须找到
It's irreplaceable! We have to find out where it went.
我们必须找回来
We have to get it back.
-但妈妈  里面是什么  -很重要的东西
- But, Mom, what is it? - It's important.
玛格拉  听着
Maghra, listen--
你能不能...
Please can you just--
别让我再多解释了  就帮我找到
Don't ask me to say anything more. Just help me find it.
亲爱的  我们没有武器
My love, we are unarmed.
昨晚无论谁来过  都可能返回
Whoever came last night may return.
而且猎巫者在外面游荡找寻
And the Witchfinder lurks out there somewhere.
如果我们待得太久  他会找到我们
If we remain too long, he will find us.
那我们得赶紧了
Then we must hurry.
我的父亲  我和他的关系
My father, my relationship with him
我不知道如何开口阐述
is not something I know how to talk about.
很复杂
It's complicated.
我觉得你应该最能理解这点
And, of all people, I would think you would understand.
无论我向你隐瞒了什么
Whatever secrets I have kept from you
这秘密都一直保护了我们
has been to protect us.
无论你向我隐瞒了什么
Whatever secrets you have kept from me
这秘密也一直保护了我们
has always been to protect us.
拜托让我理解一下
Please help me understand this.
告诉我为什么要现在
Help me justify putting our children
置我们的孩子于险境  因为我做不到
in danger right now because I cannot.
我知道
I know.
里面有什么这么重要  你连说都不能说
What could possibly be so important and still you'll not say it?
-我去找  -不行
- I'll do it. - No.
哈妮瓦
Haniwa.
她已经知道你的诉求了
She already knows everything you're asking.
我会替你找到
I'll find it for you.
如果是江匪  他们离我们半日的路程
If it were river bandits, they're half a day away.
如果是奥派罗族  可能有上百人
If it was the Opayol, there could be hundreds of them.
上百个看不见我的人
A hundred of them won't see me coming.
你知道我们逃脱猎巫者的追捕有多幸运吗
Do you know how fortunate we were to escape the Witchfinder?
非常幸运
Very fortunate.
又一次没有武器的打斗吗
Another fight and now without arms?
我不是说要进行打斗  爸爸
I'm not suggesting we get into a fight, Papa.
无论是谁拿的
Whoever took it...
如果他们不知道我在那  又怎么跟我打斗
how can they fight me if they don't even know that I'm there?
再说  我们都不知道他们是谁
And besides, we don't know who they are.
我们应该至少搞清楚
We should at least try to figure out--
我想我知道
I think I know.
-什么  -我想我知道是谁拿了我们的东西
- What? - I think I know who took our things.
-你在说什么  -你看
- What are you talking about? - Look, please.
是什么  你们看到什么了
What is it? What do you see?
告诉我  是什么
Tell me. What is it?
告诉我
Tell me.
到时候了  女王陛下
It is time, my queen.
安夫人所说的话已传开
News of Lady An's parlor has spread.
集体示威的人群
Demonstrations in protest of you
抗议您杀害了好几个受尊敬的大人
having killed several beloved lords
从下层城墙开始涌动
have begun about the lower wall.
宫殿卫兵将他们堵在了海湾处
The palace guard keeps them at bay,
但我不知道能维持多久
but for how long I do not know.
女王陛下
My queen?
接下去会怎样
What happens next?
剩余的大人集合到了一起
The remaining lords are convening.
如果他们取得了暴徒的信任
If they gain the trust of the mob,
说不好他们会怎么做
there's no telling what they may do.
父啊  您的大能我们能感知  却触摸不到
Father, whose power we feel but cannot touch...
我接受我的命运
I accept my fate.
我感谢您能让我选择生死时辰
I thank you that I could choose its hour.
杰拉马瑞尔  你没有来找我  我的爱人
Jerlamarel, you did not come for me, my love.
所以我来找你了
So I am coming to you.